ARMUGHAN AHMED

Software Engineer

+4915739711228 armughan.ahmed@yahoo.com www.linkedin.com/in/armughanahmed github.com/armughanahmed Gieshügeler Str 16, 97218 Gerbrunn



SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over **3 years** of experience in **.NET, Spring Boot, Angular, Azure,** and **DevOps.** Led development of several projects estimating their worth over **\$8 million**. I'm a motivated software engineer who has developed, designed, and maintained several high quality software.

My Portfolio Website

SKILLS

Backend:

.NET, C#, Azure Functions, Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Microservices, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C, C++, Go, Blockchain, Solidity, Ethereum, web3.js, Smart Contracts, Openzeppelin, Hyperledger Fabric, SQL, SQL Server, MySQL, PostgresSQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Entity Framework, JPA, Hibernate, Git

Frontend:

Angular, React, RxJS, PrimeNG, Angular Material, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Infrastructure:

Azure, AWS, GCP, CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Redis, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Azure Service Bus, Grafana, Ansible

Testing: Chai, Mocha, xUnit, JUnit, Mockito

EXPERIENCE

CONSULTANT DEVELOPMENT

Karachi, Pakistan 07/2021 - 04/2024

Systems Limited systemsItd.com

Y. Hata Customer Portal

- · Worked on a customer portal and achieved a remarkable 5x performance boost compared to their old ERP System
- Integrated Microsoft Dynamics D365 using OData Protocol in the portal and created CronJobs for syncing data periodically
- Created REST APIs with .NET 6, Spring Boot 3 and seamlessly deployed application on Azure App Service using Azure DevOps CI/CD
- · Developed frontend components using **Angular 17** used **modular design** and **smart&dumb** components pattern techniques
- Enhanced the data synchronization architecture, achieving a 10x efficiency using parallel processing with Azure Queue Service and Entity Framework Bulk methods.
- · Success Story: Y. Hata Customer Portal

Live Commerce - The Ultimate Livestreaming Shopping Platform

- · Ideated and Created a Live Streaming Platform for sellers where they can host **livestreaming** shows to sell directly to a global audience
- Compressed, Encoded, and transcoded videos in different formats to serve content more efficiently using Azure Media Services
- · Implemented a Live Comment Feature using Azure SignalR, where buyers could interact with sellers during their live streams
- · Rest APIs were built using .NET 6 and frontend was built using Angular 13
- · Whitepaper: Live Commerce

JNI Sales Portal Mobile And Web

- · Built an Enterprise Portal for a merchandise distribution company and integrated Microsoft Dynamics (D365)
- · Reduced the infrastructure cost by more than 80% by devising a serverless architecture using Azure Functions
- · Implemented an event driven architecture using Azure Queue Service and SignalR for real time data sync
- · Implemented Azure AD Authentication using MSAL
- · Reduced the upfront infrastructure and computational cost for JNI and autoscaled the application during sales by
- · Reduced JNI's Branding Consultant's ordering processing time to almost 5x compared to their legacy portal
- · Website: MyNadel

EXPERIENCE

DEVOPS INTERN Karachi, Pakistan

iVolve Technologies Pvt. Ltd. 02/2021 - 06/2021

ivolve.io

QCloud - Pakistan's First Public Cloud

- · Created a CI/CD Pipeline for QA Environment using Jenkins and Groovy Script
- · Built an Infrastructure as Code using Terraform
- · Created deployment and service files for Keycloak and deployed it on Kubernetes cluster

BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

Karachi, Pakistan

08/2020 - 11/2020

Xord xord.com

XIO Flash Token

- · Created Flash Token Smart Contract using Solidity 0.7.4 and Openzeppelin on Ethereum Chain
- · Created Subgraphs using The Graph Protocol for querying on the Ethereum Chain
- Built a tweets scrapper using Python 3, that scraped tweets of XIO token holders who participated in the Flash staking competition
- · Created an XIO Token Distribution Bot using Node.js, Web3.js
- · Researched on gas fees optimizations and proposed a Layer 2 solution on Matic Network

EDUCATION

MSc Informatik

Julius Maximilians Universität Würzburg

Würzburg

04/2024 - Present

BS Computer Science

Karachi, Pakistan

National University of Computer & Emerging Sciences, German grade 2,4/1,0

08/2017 - 07/2021

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Blocktrade - Supply Chain Management Using Blockchain (FYP)

11/2020 - 07/2021

github.com/armughanahmed/blocktrade

Node.js, Express, Golang, React.js, MySQL, Hyperledger Fabric, CouchDB, Docker

- Blocktrade is a supply chain management system which optimizes the supply chain processes. The transactions are recorded on a private blockchain i.e. Hyperledger Fabric and the state is maintained using CouchDB. smart contracts are made using Golang
- · Certificate Authority for each peer organization. Transactions are signed using each organization's private key
- · Kafka consensus used by the ordering service
- · End-to-End consignment tractability
- · Verification of documents involved in Supply Chain process
- · Provides shipping companies information to the cargo owner based on the selected schedule

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

Star Of The Quarter Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Systems Limited, 2023 Microsoft, 2022

Star Of The Quarter Dean's List

Systems Limited, 2022 National University of Computer & Emerging Sciences -

FAST, 2022

LANGUAGES

English (C1) German (Beginner)